Harvard University. Corporation. Records of land and property owned by Harvard University, 1643-1835: an inventory
Records of land and property owned by Harvard University, 1643-1835
- XII. Narragansett farm, 1696-1829, 1.12 cubic feet (2 document boxes and 6 oversize folders)
  - Letter from Joseph Denison to Ebenezer Storer about Narragansett farm, Nov. 24, 1781, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 80
  - Letter from Joseph Denison to Ebenezer Storer about Narragansett farm, March 28, 1782, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 81
  - Letter from Joseph Denison to Ebenezer Storer about Narragansett farm, Feb. 27, 1783 and draft of Storer’s reply, March 26, 1783, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 82
  - Letter from Huling Gardiner to Thomas Story, Nov. 22, 1785, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 83
    Huling Gardiner, Nicholas Gardiner's son, was a tenant on the farm. He wrote to tell Story that Joseph Denison recently died and to request a written lease for the farm, which Denison had promised but did not deliver.
  - Statement of the Estate of Joseph Denison’s account with Harvard College, March 29, 1786, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 84
  - Statement of Huling Gardiner’s account with Harvard College, Aug. 18, 1787, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 85
  - Letter from Rouse J. Helme to Ebenezer Storer, Aug. 20, 1787, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 86
    Helme replaced Joseph Denison as Harvard’s local representative regarding the farm until his death in 1789.
  - Copy of Rouse J. Helme’s receipts of payment from Huling Gardiner for rent of Narragansett farm, May-Aug. 1788, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 87
  - Letter from Amos Gardner to Ebenezer Storer requesting to lease Narragansett farm, March 8, 1790, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 88
  - Letter from James Helme to Ebenezer Storer, March 10, 1790, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 89
    James Helme was the brother of Rouse J. Helme. Storer offered the position of managing farm affairs to him when his brother died in 1789, but he declined, suggesting Benjamin Weight as a suitable candidate for the position.
  - Letter from Huling Gardiner to Ebenezer Storer, June 1, 1793, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 90
  - Letter from Huling Gardiner to Ebenezer Storer, Dec. 20, 1794, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 91
  - Letter from Daniel Updike to Ebenezer Storer, Feb. 4, 1796, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 92
    Letter concerns the delivery of Huling Gardiner’s rent.
  - Letter from Huling Gardiner to Ebenezer Storer, May 14, 1796, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 93
  - Letter from Huling Gardiner to Ebenezer Storer, Aug. 19, 1799, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 94
  - Letter from Huling Gardiner to Ebenezer Storer, Dec. 18, 1800, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 95
  - Letter from Huling Gardiner to Ebenezer Storer, Jan. 1, 1801, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 96
  - Memorandum about Narragansett farm and statement of Rouse J. Helme’s account with Harvard College, prepared by Ebenezer Storer, May 20, 1801, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 97
  - Letters from Huling Gardiner to Ebenezer Storer, April 30, 1801 and May 28, 1801, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 98
  - Letter from Peleg Brown to Ebenezer Storer, June 22, 1801, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 99
    Brown wanted to buy the farm.
  - Letter from Peleg Brown to Ebenezer Storer, July 22, 1801, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 100
  - Letter from Nathaniel Church to “Deacon Storey” (Ebenezer Storer?) requesting lease of Narragansett farm, Jan. 23, 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 101
    Note on verso: “John Cottrell in North Kingston or Wickford will give $3,000 for Farm in Narragansett.”
  - Memorandum about Narragansett farm, ca. Jan. 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 102
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to Ebenezer Storer about Narragansett farm, Feb. 18, 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 103
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to Ebenezer Storer advising him on Narragansett farm, Feb. 24, 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 104
  - Letters from Huling Gardiner to Ebenezer Storer, May 21, 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 105
  - Letter from Nathaniel Church to Ebenezer Storer requesting lease of Narragansett farm, June 29, 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 5, Folder 106
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to Ebenezer Storer advising him on Narragansett farm, Aug. 24, 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 1
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to Ebenezer Storer, Sept. 3, 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 2
  - Eliphalet Pearson’s memoranda about Narragansett farm, ca. 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 3
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to Ebenezer Storer about the trees on Narragansett farm, March 31, 1803, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 4
  - Letter from Daniel Updike to Eliphalet Pearson about the cost of erecting a sawmill on Narragansett farm, June 3, 1803, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 5
  - Letter from Huling Gardiner to Ebenezer Storer about the cost of building a barn on Narragansett farm, July 25, 1803, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 6
  - Letter from Nathaniel Church to Ebenezer Storer(?) requesting lease of Narragansett farm, Aug. 22, 1803, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 7
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to Ebenezer Storer advising him to sell the wood on Narragansett farm, March 12, 1805, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 8
  - Plan of Narragansett farm, with notes concerning soil and timber, ca. 1805?, UAI 15.750 Oversize cabinet, Folder 7
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to John Davis about Narragansett farm, Jan. 15, 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 9
    Postscript reads: “I presume you have seen Mr. Elliot’s resolve respecting the Indians - - What’s in his design? Good or bad ~”
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to Jonathan Jackson about Narragansett farm, Feb. 7, 1807 and draft of Jackson’s reply, Feb. 12, 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 10
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to Jonathan Jackson about Narragansett farm, March 24, 1807 and notes from Jackson’s response, March 28, 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 11
  - Harvard Corporation vote authorizing the sale of wood from Narragansett farm, May 19, 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 12
  - Draft of letter from Jonathan Jackson to David Leonard Barnes about Narragansett farm, June 2, 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 13
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to Jonathan Jackson about Narragansett farm, Aug. 20, 1807 and draft of Jackson’s reply, Aug. 22, 1807, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 14
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to Jonathan Jackson about the recent sale of wood from Narragansett farm, Jan. 14, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 15
  - John Carlile and Samuel Carlile’s bill to David Leonard Barnes for shingles sent to Narragansett farm, July-Aug. 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 16
  - Hercules Whitney’s bill to David Leonard Barnes for nails and shingles, Sept. 17, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 17
  - Oliver Carpenter’s bill to David Leonard Barnes for squares of glass sent to Narragansett farm, Sept. 30, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 18
  - William Reynold’s bill to David Leonard Barnes for work on Narragansett farm, lumber, and putty, Oct. 3, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 19
    Bill was paid Dec. 18, 1808.
  - Samuel Shearman’s bill to David Leonard Barnes for lumber, hinges, room and board of laborers, and other services on Narragansett farm, Oct. 4, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 20
    Bill was paid April 15, 1809.
  - Plan of Narragansett farm, drawn by surveyor Daniel Anthony, Oct. 28, 1808, UAI 15.750 Oversize cabinet, Folder 8
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to Jonathan Jackson about Narragansett farm, Oct. 30, 1808 and draft of letter from Jackson to “Judge Parsons,” Dec. 3, 1808, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 21
  - Samuel D. Allen’s bill to David Leonard Barnes for food and lodging of farm surveyor, “horsekeeping,” and other goods and services, Oct. 1808-Jan. 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 22
  - Account of timber and wood from Narragansett farm sold at public auction, Jan. 4, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 23
  - Samuel Carter’s receipt of payment of auctioneer’s fees, Jan. 4, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 24
    Carter was paid five dollars for serving as auctioneer in the auction of wood from Narragansett farm, held on Jan. 4, 1809.
  - Letters from David Leonard Barnes to Jonathan Jackson, Jan. 7, 1809 and Jan. 13, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 25
  - Draft of letter from Jonathan Jackson to “Judge Parsons” (intended for David Leonard Barnes?), Jan. 15, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 26
  - List of notes taken for wood sold on Narragansett farm, Jan. 16, 1809 and memorandum regarding Benjamin C. Gardner’s notes for wood, undated, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 27
  - Letters from David Leonard Barnes to Jonathan Jackson, Jan. 17, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 28
  - Drafts of three letters from Jonathan Jackson to David Leonard Barnes, Jan. 17, 1809; Jan. 18, 1809 (mistakenly written “June”); and Jan. 19, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 29
  - Jesse Bicknell’s receipt of payment for carrying chain to survey Narragansett farm, Jan. 25, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 30
  - Letters from David Leonard Barnes to Jonathan Jackson, Jan. 30, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 31
  - Draft of letter from Jonathan Jackson to David Leonard Barnes, Feb. 1, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 32
  - Receipt to David Leonard Barnes for delivering promissory notes from the sale of wood on Narragansett farm, July 18, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 33
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to Jonathan Jackson, Aug. 31, 1809; draft of letter from Jackson to Caleb Gannett, Sept. 2, 1809; and draft of Jackson’s reply to Barnes, Sept. 2, 1809, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 34
  - Letter from David Leonard Barnes to Jonathan Jackson, Jan. 5, 1810 and draft of Jackson’s reply, Jan. 9, 1810, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 35
  - Letter from Thomas Burgess to John Davis, March 17, 1827 and statement of Burgess’ account with Harvard College, 1826-1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 36
  - Letter from Thomas Burgess to Ebenezer Francis, March 21, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 37
  - Manuscript copy of Thomas Burgess’ circular letter about the sale of Narragansett farm and statements from fourteen individuals about the value of the farm, March 29, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 38
  - Broadside notice of sale of Narragansett farm, March 30, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 26
  - Letter from Thomas Burgess to Ebenezer Francis advising on the sale of Narragansett farm, April 9, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 39
  - Manuscript copy of Harvard Corporation vote authorizing sale of Narragansett farm, April 19, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 40
  - Letter from Thomas Burgess to Ebenezer Francis, April 21, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 41
  - Letter from Thomas Burgess to Ebenezer Francis, May 11, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 42
  - Plan of Narragansett farm, drawn by surveyor Robert F. Noyes, May 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 27
  - Statement of auction sales of Narragansett farm by John Hall, Auctioneer, June 23, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 43
  - Letter from Thomas Burgess to Ebenezer Francis with account of auction sales of Narragansett farm, June 23-25, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 44
  - Letter from Thomas Burgess to Ebenezer Francis, June 28, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 45
  - Letter from George Burgess to Ebenezer Francis, July 5, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 46
    George Burgess, son of Thomas, wrote this brief letter to acknowledge receipt of the deeds of the Narragansett farm in his father’s absence.
  - Account of sales of Narragansett farm at June 23, 1827 auction, drafted by Thomas Russell on July 19, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 47
  - Letter from Thomas Burgess to Ebenezer Francis, July 29, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 48
  - Letter from Thomas Burgess to Ebenezer Francis and statement of Burgess’ account with Harvard College, Aug. 2, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 49
  - Letters from Thomas Burgess to Ebenezer Francis, Aug. 10, 1827; Sept. 26, 1827; and Oct. 8, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 50
  - Letters from Thomas Burgess to Ebenezer Francis, Oct. 15, 1827; Oct. 24, 1827; and Dec. 15, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 51
  - Letters from Thomas Burgess to Ebenezer Francis, Dec. 26, 1827 and Dec. 31, 1827, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 52
  - Statement of Thomas Burgess’ account with Harvard College, Jan. 7, 1829, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 53
- XIII. Townsend, 1733-1802, .16 cubic feet (14 legal folders and 1 oversize folder)
  Records in this series pertain to a 250 acre lot in Townsend, Massachusetts granted to Harvard College by the General Court in 1719, at the same time another lot of the same size in neighboring Lunenburg was also granted to the College (See Series XI). Although Townsend was within the borders of Massachusetts at the time of the grant, it was determined to be part of New Hampshire when the province line between Massachusetts and New Hampshire was established in 1741, and thus no longer College property. As an indemnity, the General Court granted another tract of land in Massachusetts to Harvard in 1765, but that land was re-granted to another party at a later date, overriding the College's rights to it. This series contains correspondence about the land, several plots drawn by surveyors, bills for survey work, memoranda, and a letter explaining the claim that the land lay in New Hampshire.
  Drake, Samuel Adams. History of Middlesex County, Massachusetts, containing carefully prepared histories of every city and town in the county. Boston: Estes and Lauriat, 1880.
  - Corporation vote concerning College land in Townsend, Oct. 19, 1733 and letter from Benjamin Wadsworth, Henry Flynt, and Andrew Bordman to surveyor Samuel Jones, Nov. 26, 1733, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 54
    The Corporation appointed Wadsworth, Flynt, and Bordman as Committee members to deal with College lands in Townsend, and to hire surveyor Samuel Jones to investigate the land on behalf of the College.
  - Vote of Proprietors of Townsend to appoint a committee to lay out a lot of land for Harvard, April 14, 1734, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 55
    Verso reads: “Townshend proprietors vote, recd. of Capt. Lawrence, March 9, 1735/6.”
  - Memorandum about payment of Samuel Jones and Moses Bordman for work related to College land in Townsend, April 23, 1734, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 56
    Moses Bordman was hired to assist Jones.
  - Instruction of Samuel Jones and Moses Bordman to survey Townsend land, April 23, 1734, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 57
  - Moses Bordman’s bill for survey work in Townsend, April 29, 1734 and his account of the land’s boundaries, May 1, 1734, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 58
    These are on the same document. Bordman’s bill lists the costs of various items, including gingerbread, 2 quarts of rum, “chees,” and money “for keeping [his] horse.”
  - Townsend proprietors committee’s description of the boundaries of College land, May 2, 1734, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 59
    The committee of Townsend proprietors who established these boundaries consisted of William Lawrance, Jasher Wyman, and Amos Whitney.
  - Benjamin Wadsworth’s memorandum noting payment of Moses Bordman and Samuel Jones, May 6, 1734, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 60
  - Appointment of Moses Bordman as Harvard’s representative concerning Townsend land, Feb. 5, 1734/5, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 61
  - Manuscript copy of letter from Benjamin Wadsworth to William Lawrance about Townsend land, April 15, 1735, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 62
  - Memorandum related to Stephen Prentice’s news about Townsend land, April 28, 1735, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 63
    Prentice reported that Samuel Jones’ measurement of part of the land “fell short in ye measure on one side.”
  - Townsend proprietors committee’s description of boundaries of College land, Dec. 1735, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 64
    Verso reads: “Committee for Townshend Lands, recd of Capt. Lawrence, March 9, 1735/6.”
  - Plan and description of College land in Townsend, created by surveyor John Stevens, Dec. 1735, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 28
    Recto signed by William Lawrence, Jasher Wyman, and Amos Whitney, members of a committee. Note on verso: “Plat of Coll. Farm at Townshend, recd. of Capt. Lawrence. March 9, 1735/6” with other notations and calculations
  - Plan and description of sixty-seven acres of College land in Townsend, created by surveyor John Stevens, June 13, 1739, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 65
    Signed by committee members William Lawrence, Jasher Wyman, and Amos Whitney. Verso contains Edward Holyoke’s instructions to Andrew Bordman to pay William Lawrence for unspecified services.
  - Letter from Jasher Wyman to the Harvard Overseers about a claim on the Townsend land, Dec. 19, 1750, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 66
    Wyman wrote to inform them that the College land in Townsend fell within a claim for land held by John Mason (and extending into New Hampshire).
  - Eliphalet Pearson’s memorandum on Townsend land, ca. 1802, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 67
- XIV. Waltham farm (Rogers Farm), 1737-1826, .55 cubic feet (1 document box and 5 oversize folders)
  In 1738, Harvard purchased a farm of approximately 160 acres in Waltham, Massachusetts from Anthony Caverly with proceeds from the sale of the Rowley lands bequeathed to the College by Ezekiel Rogers (See Series I). The farm was often referred to as Rogers Farm, in honor of the source of the purchasing funds, and it was leased to generate income. Although some tenants paid their rent in "lawful silver money," others paid with beef, pork, Indian corn, cider, butter, cheese, potatoes, rye, oats, barley, melons, squashes, flax, and hay. Several Harvard employees were among the tenants, including Hollis Professor of Mathematics and Natural Philosophy Samuel Williams and College Steward Caleb Gannett. The other tenants documented in these records were William Hagar, Thomas Dean, Ephraim Pierce (sometimes spelled "Peirce"), Jonathan Sanderson, and Nahum Hardy. The farm was sold in 1835 for $5,000, which became the Ezekiel Rogers Fund.
  This series contains records related to the rental of the farm, as well as several plans of the land and buildings drawn by surveyors. Included are the 1738 deed of sale from Caverly to Harvard, memoranda about labor performed on the farm by tenants (which was taken into account when determining the rent they owed), leases and minutes for leases, statements of account with tenants and with individuals who made repairs on the property; bonds; memoranda; a certification of taxes made by the Waltham assessors; reports on the farm's production; and accounts of timber from the farm either sold or brought to the Harvard wood-yard.
  Of note in this series are two documents created by John Hancock during his tenure as Treasurer of Harvard College.
  - Manuscript copy of deed of mortgage, Anthony Caverly to James Smith, Oct. 15, 1737, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 68
    This document appears to have been copied for Edward Hutchinson on Aug. 11, 1740.
  - Lease of Waltham farm to William Hagar, March 25, 1738, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 17
    Signed by John Caverly, John Larrabee, and Edward Hutchinson.
  - Deed of sale for Waltham farm, Anthony Caverly to the President and Fellows of Harvard College, April 4, 1738, UAI 15.750 Oversize cabinet, Folder 9
    Harvard paid “two thousand pounds in good bills of publick credit” for the farm.
  - Certification of Anthony Caverly’s April 1738 sale of Waltham farm to the President and Fellows of Harvard College, Aug. 8, 1741, UAI 15.750 Box 6, Folder 69
  - Manuscript copy of minutes of agreement with Jos. Walker about making pasture (on Waltham farm?), Oct. 27, 1746, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 18
  - “Roger’s Farm 1748 Partially transcribed fragments", UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 19
    The contents of this mold-damaged document have not been determined. This folder title was transcribed from its former housing.
  - Minutes of lease of Waltham farm to Thomas Dean, Jan. 8, 1750, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 20
  - Lease of Waltham farm to Thomas Dean, Oct. 16, 1750, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 21
    Signed by Thomas Dean, Edward Holyoke, Samuel Gookin, and Samuel Winsloop(?). Verso contains addenda made between 1752 and 1756. States that rent was to be paid in “lawful silver money” as well as beef, pork, Indian corn, butter and “cyder.”
  - Accounts of work on Waltham farm: Benjamin Johnson for surveying and Ebenezer Braddish for leading windows, Nov. 20, 1750, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 22
  - Plan of Waltham farm, made by Benjamin Johnson, Nov. 20, 1750, UAI 15.750 Box 8, Folder 29
  - Thomas Dean’s account of work done on Waltham farm, 1750, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 23
  - Calculations for adjustment of Thomas Dean’s rent for Waltham farm, 1750, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 24
  - Settlement between Thomas Dean and the Harvard committee on Waltham farm regarding Dean’s rent, Jan. 17, 1750/1, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 25
  - Account of settlement between Thomas Dean and the Harvard committee on Waltham farm regarding Dean’s rent, Jan. 17, 1750/1, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 26
  - Bond of Thomas Dean and Jonathan Smith to Harvard College for performance of articles of lease of Waltham farm, Nov. 17, 1750/1, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 27
    Signed by Samuel Gookin, Samuel Winsloop(?), Thomas Dean, and Jonathan Smith.
  - Account of Thomas Dean’s rent of Waltham farm through March 1752, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 28
  - Memorandum by Edward Holyoke concerning balance due by Thomas Dean, Jan. 16, 1753, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 29
  - Account of Thomas Dean in regards to Waltham farm, Jan. 18, 1753, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 30
    Account covers the years 1751-1753.
  - Adjustment of Thomas Dean’s rent for Waltham farm for the years prior to March 25, 1753, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 31
  - Statement of Thomas Dean’s account with Harvard College, regarding Waltham farm, March 25, 1753, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 32
  - Memorandum regarding Thomas Dean’s labor on Waltham farm, Jan. 11, 1754, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 33
    Signed by Dean, who indicates that account was settled on Jan. 16, 1754
  - Statement of Thomas Dean’s account with Harvard College, regarding Waltham farm, Jan. 16, 1754, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 34
    Sent to Thomas Hubbard by Edward Holyoke.
  - Adjustment of Thomas Dean’s rent for Waltham farm to March 25, 1754, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 35
  - Calculations for adjustment of Thomas Dean’s rent for Waltham farm, 1754, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 36
  - Adjustment of Thomas Dean’s rent for Waltham farm to March 25, 1755, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 37
  - Agreement with Thomas Dean about building a wall and moving the barn on Waltham farm, March 25, 1755, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 38
    Verso describes the document as “Minutes of Mr. Dean’s lease determining.”
  - Letter from Edward Holyoke to Thomas Hubbard regarding new tenant (Ephraim Pierce) on Waltham farm, April 24, 1755, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 39
  - Memorandum regarding Ephraim Pierce’s labor on Waltham farm, March 31, 1756, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 40
  - Corrections to the account of Ephraim Pierce, March 31, 1756, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 41
  - Adjustment of Ephraim Pierce’s rent for Waltham farm to March 1756, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 42
  - Lease of Waltham farm to Ephraim Pierce, April 16, 1756, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 43
  - Lease of Waltham farm to Ephraim Pierce, 1756(?) (2 copies), UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 44
  - Receipt for Ephraim Pierce’s rent payment, June 29, 1758, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 45
    Issued and signed by Thomas Hubbard.
  - Fragment of document concerning Ephraim Pierce’s account, 1757-1758, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 46
  - Lease of Waltham farm to Ephraim Pierce, April 1, 1759, UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 47
    Signed by Edward Holyoke, Ephraim Pierce, Joseph Mayhew, and Elizabeth Holyoke. May 21, 1760 addendum notes received payment.
  - Lease of Waltham farm to Ephraim Pierce, April 1, 1759 (second copy), UAI 15.750 Box 11, Folder 48
    Signed by Ephraim Pierce, Edward Holyoke, Joseph Mayhew, and Elizabeth Holyoke.